(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-08-01T12:55:18.034919",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.1-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
Once upon a time, there was a girl named Ina'nis.
She spent her days singing by the lake.
But one day,
She woke up somewhere else.
過ぎ去る 季節が過ぎ
As the passing seasons go by,
風がまた 熱を連れてくる
the wind brings back the warmth once again.
何千回も巡って 何万回も輝く
Revolving thousands of times, shining tens of thousands of times,
そうやって 光が生まれる
that is how light is born.
切なさが溶けてる 空の向こう どこまでも遠い青
Beyond the sky where sorrow melts, into the distant blue...
スピードを上げた
I picked up the speed.
想い立ち
The thoughts that sped up
自分の意志で 今飛び立つよ
now take flight by their own will.
感じている
I can feel
無邪気な誓い
that innocent vow,
言葉は知らない
but I don't know what to say.
流れていく
Flowing onward
水の行方に 心を馳せよう
towards where the water goes, I send my heart.
透き通る季節が過ぎ
The clear season passes by,
風がまた熱を連れてくる
and the wind brings its warmth once more.
傷あとは 消えていたわ
The scars have disappeared,
溢れだす 情熱のシンフォニー
a symphony of overflowing passion.
何千回も廻って
Spinning around thousands of times,
何万回も輝く
shining hundreds of thousands of times,
そうやって光が生まれる
and so, light is born.
忘れじの言の葉
Wasureji no Kotonooha
言の葉を紡いで 微笑んだ泡沫
Weaving the words, a fleeting dream,
旅人迷い込む 御伽の深い霧
a wanderer lost in the deep fog of fairy tales.
差し伸べた掌
Stretching out a palm,
そっと触れる予感
with a premonition of gentle touch.
受け止めて零れた
Catching the drop that spilled over,
光の一滴
a single droplet of light.
面影虚ろって 微笑んだ幻
Fading shadows, a smiling illusion,
想いの果てる場所 まだ遥か遠くで
where hope is fulfilled is still far away.
求め探して彷徨って やがて詠われて
Searching and seeking, wandering, and eventually sung,
幾千幾万幾億の旋律となる
becoming thousands, tens of thousands, billions of melodies.
いつか失い 奪われて消える運命でも
Even if destined to be lost, stolen, and vanish someday,
それは忘れられることなき 物語
it is a story that will never be forgotten.
指先を絡めて 触れる誰かの夢
Entwining fingertips, touching someone's dream,
刻まれた想いの こだまだけが響く
only the echoes of carved feelings resonate.
いつか失い 奪われて消える運命でも
Even if destined to be lost, stolen, and vanish someday,
それは忘れられることなき ここにある物語
it is a story that is saved right here without being forgotten.
求め探して彷徨って やがて道となり
Searching and seeking, wandering, and becoming the path,
幾千幾万幾億の英雄は往く
thousands, tens of thousands, billions of heroes proceed.
いつか失い 奪われて消える運命でも
Even if destined to be lost, stolen, and vanish someday,
それは忘れられることなき 此処に在る
it is a story that remains right here.
言の葉を紡いで 微笑んだ泡沫
Weaving the words, a fleeting dream,
旅人の名前を 御伽話と言う
the name of the wanderer is called a fairy tale.
求め探して彷徨って やがて詠われて
Searching and seeking, wandering, and eventually sung,
幾千幾万幾億の旋律となる
becoming thousands, tens of thousands, billions of melodies.
いつか失い 奪われて消える運命でも
Even if destined to be lost, stolen, and vanish someday,
それは忘れられることなき 物語
it is a story that cannot be forgotten.
求め探して彷徨って やがて道となり
Searching and seeking, wandering, and becoming the path,
幾千幾万幾億の英雄は往く
thousands, tens of thousands, billions of heroes proceed.
いつか失い 奪われて消える運命でも
Even if destined to be lost, stolen, and vanish someday,
それは忘れられることなき ここにある物語
it is a story that is saved right here without being forgotten.
君の中にある 赤と青き線
Red lines, blue lines you carry inside
それが結ばれるのは 心の臓
The twain shall meet at the center of your heart
風の中でも負けないような声で
In a voice that withstands the wind
届ける言葉を今は育ててる
I'm bringing up the words to deliver
時はまくるめ 風はにきはだ
Time is a sleeper, wind is a soft skin
星はうぶすな 人はかげろう
Star is a cradle, people are mirage
なんで泣いてるのと 聞かれ答えれる
Why am I crying? When asked, I can answer
涙なんかじゃ
It's far from just tears...
君の中にある 赤と青き線
Red lines, blue lines you carry inside
それが結ばれるのは 心の臓
The twain shall meet at the center of your heart
風の中でも負けないような声で
In a voice that withstands the wind
届ける言葉を今は育ててる
I'm bringing up the words to deliver
時はまくるめ 風はにきはだ
Time is a sleeper, wind is a soft skin
星はうぶすな 人はかげろう
Star is a cradle, people are mirage
なんで泣いてるのと 聞かれ答えれる
Why am I crying? When asked, I can answer
涙なんかじゃ
It's far from just tears...
僕ら出逢えたことの意味には まるで
For the meaning of us meeting, it's as if
追いつかない
We can never catch up to it
この身ひとつじゃ 足りない叫び
With this body alone, our cries are not enough
君の手に関わった時にだけ震えた
Trembling only when I touched your hand,
心があったよ
There was a heart there
意味をいくつ越えれば僕らは辿り
How many meanings must we cross to reach
着けるのかな
Where we're going?
愚かさでいい 醜さでいい
It's okay to be foolish, it's okay to be ugly
正しさのその先で 君と手を取りたい
Beyond righteousness, I want to take your hand
思い出せない
I can't remember
大切な記憶
Precious memories
言葉にならない
Feelings that cannot become words
ここにある想い
The thoughts that exist here
もしかしたら もしかしたら
Maybe, maybe
それだけでこの心はできている
My heart is made of just that
もしかしたら もしかしたら
Maybe, maybe
君に「気づいて」と今もその胸を
Still beating against that chest, saying "Please notice"
打ち鳴らす
Resonating within you
思い出せない 大切な記憶
I can't remember precious memories
言葉にならない ここにある想い
Feelings that cannot become words, thoughts right here
もしかしたら もしかしたら
Maybe, maybe
それだけでこの心はできている
My heart is made of just that
もしかしたら もしかしたら
Maybe, maybe
君に「気づいて」と今もその胸を
Still beating against that chest, saying "Please notice"
打ち鳴らす
Resonating within you
なんで泣いてるのと 聞かれ答えれる
Why am I crying? When asked, I can answer
涙なんかじゃ
It's far from just tears...
僕ら出逢えたことの意味には まるで
For the meaning of us meeting, it's as if
追いつかない
We can never catch up to it
この身ひとつじゃ 足りない叫び
With this body alone, our cries are not enough
君の手に関わった時にだけ震えた
Trembling only when I touched your hand,
心があったよ
There was a heart there
意味をいくつ越えれば僕らは辿り
How many meanings must we cross to reach
着けるのかな
Where we're going?
愚かさでいい 醜さでいい
It's okay to be foolish, it's okay to be ugly
正しさのその先で
Beyond righteousness...
今さ その先で 君と生きてきたい
Right now, beyond that, I want to live with you...
Wow, hello everyone!
Good morning, afternoon, evening!
How are you guys doing?
Are you all miraculously pr- pr- pr- preserved...
...I can't talk! Are you all miraculously preserved?
Yay! I can hear you guys. Yay, yay, Ina, wa, wa, wa, wahai!
Good to see you guys.
Welcome to my birthday live! We made it in time this year!
Let's go!
And of course, don't forget to, you know, talk about it, take screenshots, you know, share it with everyone using the hashtag over here...
And of course, don't forget to talk about it, take screenshots, and share it with everyone using the hashtag over here...
Yeah, so that I can also, you know, read what you guys have...
Yeah, so that I can also read what you guys have...
...thought about while watching the stream and stuff.
And yeah, of course, you know, let us talk about, uh... Where are we? Where are we?
And yeah, of course, let us talk about... where are we? Where are we?
I just went through a door and suddenly we ended up in this... I don't know, it almost looks like we're inside a storybook or something.
I have no idea where we are, but you know what, we're gonna roll with it cause that's what we do.
And of course, let us not forget, my clothes also changed!
Look! Do I look cute?
Wow, and of course, you know, look at all the details, my my flaps have gotten longer.
Wow, and of course, look at all the details, my flaps have gotten longer.
Um, I have this cool gauntlet now. Look at this! Wow, I feel like a knight.
I feel like I can defeat all evil. Click click click click!
And of course, I got my, I don't know, three glass pens behind me. Wow, I wonder if this is my weapon? Can poke people with my glass pens.
And of course, I got my, I don't know, three glass pens behind me. Wow, I wonder if this is my weapon? I can poke people with my glass pens.
And all the details on the dress, isn't it beautiful? And look, my skirt is actually made out of Takodachis.
Ooh! That's right! And also, I can already see it, you know, you guys are going, "Oh, Ina, that's me, that's me!"
Ooh! That's right! And also, I can already see it, you guys are going, "Oh, Ina, that's me, that's me!"
But yeah, look at this beautiful, beautiful outfit. Um, of course, I gotta thank Kuroboshi Papa for designing this wonderful, wonderful outfit.
But yeah, look at this beautiful, beautiful outfit. Of course, I gotta thank Kuroboshi Papa for designing this wonderful, wonderful outfit.
Thank you, Kuroboshi Papa! You're always the the best, best in making the outfits, so yeah!
Thank you, Kuroboshi Papa! You're always the best, best at making the outfits, so yeah!
And you know, I want to talk about a lot of things, but it is my birthday, and I'm going to go have fun around here. I don't know where we are, but you know, I'm going to go look around and see where we end up. We'll see, I don't know, maybe we'll find something fun to do.
And you know, I want to talk about a lot of things, but it is my birthday, and I'm going to go have fun around here. I don't know where we are, but I'm going to go look around and see where we end up. We'll see, I don't know, maybe we'll find something fun to do.
But yeah, you know, I guess I'll see you guys around. Take care.
But yeah, I guess I'll see you guys around. Take care.
え？
Eh?
え、あれ？あき先輩じゃないですか？え、い、い、い、いなちゃん！
Eh? Huh? Isn't that Aki-senpai? Eh, I-I-I-Ina-chan!
いの、え、なんで一緒になってたんですか？
Ino! Eh, why did we end up together?
なんか、なんか影があったよう気がして気づいたら、このまま待ってたけど、いや、待ってたけど、いや、いーの、はい。
I felt like there was a shadow, and before I knew it, I was waiting like this... but yeah, waiting like this, I mean, yes.
どこ、ここ？
Where are we?
私もう知らないです。
I don't even know anymore.
いのも知らないの？
You don't know either?
知らないの！
I don't!
なんか急に、なんかドアにピュッとしたら、衣装もこれになったし、ここ、どこだ？
Suddenly, when I zipped through a door, my outfit became this too. Where are we?
そうだ。いのも知らない。かわいい。
That's right. Ina doesn't know either. Cute!
え、そう？はい、そう。
Eh, really? Yes, really.
めちゃかわいいです。よく似合ってる。よく似して。
It's super cute. It suits you so well.
お、かわいい。かわいい。わ、ありがとうございます。
Oh, cute, cute. Aw, thank you!
いや、でもここ、なんか全然知らない場所で、あき先輩がいて、なんか嬉しいな。
But yeah, here, it's a completely unfamiliar place, and Aki-senpai is here, so I'm kind of happy.
本当、そう。え、あきろぜもこのね、すりーぴーだの姿でいなと加えってお会いの実話。嬉しい！嬉しい！
Truly. Eh, AkiRosé is also in this sleepy-dancer form, meeting and joining up with Ina is actually... Happy! Happy!
実話私、あの、あき先輩と、つうか、あの、歌ったり、踊ったりやりたかったんです。
Actually, I wanted to sing and dance with Aki-senpai!
じゃあ もしかして一緒に 今日は歌うの? いいんですか?
"So... are we singing together today? Is that okay?"
わあ 歌うよ やったやった 嬉しい!
"Yay, we're singing! Yay, yay, I'm so happy!"
えーと どの曲がいいかな? うんうん ホロライブの曲もあるしね 色々ね
"Umm, which song would be good? Yeah, there are Hololive songs too, various ones."
そうですね でも なんか前半の曲の中で 一番一番好きな曲は
"That's right, but among the first-half songs, my absolute favorite song..."
やっぱり あの曲ですね!
"...is definitely that song!"
えっ? あれっ? あれですね? えーと わかんないな 言ってくんないと
"Eh? Is that it? That one? Umm, I won't know if you don't tell me."
あれですね あき先輩の こっ…
"That's right, Aki-senpai's, ko..."
ああ ちょっとセクシー セクシーダンス? セクシーダンスはいっぱいある? あっ いっぱいじゃないか!
"Ah, wait, a bit sexy, sexy dance? Are there lots of sexy dances? Ah, maybe not lots!"
でも でも なんかあき先輩だったら この曲 ですね
"But, if it's Aki-senpai, it's this song."
じゃあ 今日は一緒にシャルイース いいんですか? と、いな!
"So, today together, Shallys, is that okay? With, Ina!"
はい! よろしくお願いします! 嬉しい!
"Yes! Looking forward to it! So happy!"
シャルイース うん いなとこうやって歌うのもね 初めてなんだよね
"Shallys... yeah, singing like this with Ina is a first too."
うん
"Yeah."
やっと! やっと やっと! 嬉しい 嬉しい!
"Finally! Finally, finally! So happy, so happy!"
じゃあ じゃあ あきロゼのシャルイースは 何と言っても あきロゼの国の伝承歌
"Well then, Aki Rose's Shallys is, no matter what, Aki Rose country's traditional song."
だから 何か いなの助けになることが あるかもしれないし 一緒に歌ってパワーをね つけてもらいたいなと思うから
"So, maybe it can help Ina, and since I want you to gain power by singing together,"
はい 頑張ろう! はい じゃあ よろしくお願いします!
"Yes, let's do our best! Yes, well then, looking forward to it!"
あっ ドキドキする! はい じゃあ 行きましょうか
"Ah, my heart is pounding! Yes, well then, shall we go?"
じゃあ こっちこっちこっち……
"Now, this way, this way..."
よし! じゃあ がんばるぞ はい
"Alright! Then let's do our best, yes."
Contas hale’ilia on Shallys
While thinking of the land of rest,
Animu mita potima i ji’ulyc
I hold the light strongly and move forward.
Zi clocs ocnoclez dinau key tyn
That's right, I have many guardians.
Hap’a myukil sha lu be’iru
This happiness will shake the bells of my hometown.
Yaai didi la leu minas sak’chwa
The queen protects the sanctuary from the demon's hand.
Dig nau e minas liga dia
The king becomes a sword that slashes the demon's hand.
Dishi di las weina vetic as
Even if I am swallowed by the vortex of the otherworld,
Di mi wo ilaj molof hap’a
Blessings on her tomorrow as she starts to walk again.
Contas hale’ilia on Shallys
While thinking of the land of rest,
Animu mita potima i ji’ulyc
I hold the light strongly and move forward.
Alovia tolum stulia
This is the story of a traveler.
Non to cias stulia
And it is none other than your story.
Contas hale’ilia on Shallys
While thinking of the land of rest,
Animu mita potima i ji’ulyc
I hold the light strongly and move forward.
Zi clocs ocnoclez dinau key tyn
That's right, I have many guardians.
Hap’a myukil sha lu be’iru
This happiness will shake the bells of my hometown.
Es tuna ligali vidia
If there is something to be accomplished, you must live.
Fala to st lumia diz lomo
That death is honorable but not a virtue.
Kuls winia nina i ji’ulyc
Raise your voice, raise your fist, hold up the light.
Menelasm oc lulu
Raise your face and count your trust.
Dili lalu pi puru no do muru
The feet you stepped on carve order.
Fal’ma in vila le mam silli fri
Invited by the crying voice of the responding Pharma,
Ono mabul vaniro undal’ne
Put words into the shallow you trace with your fingers.
Dina wia salame
Let's sing it instead of that monument,
Te cant mila lila, ah~
A song of the earth that continues forever.
All feel, the scene is here
Bimola, sheroni conya
Kimi o omoi, puru poneola
Bimola, sherolula
Kondos, aleluya, o sharunis, animumita, fogimorichu
Siguos, o nocle, sino kaysin, abumayukiru, sharuberu
Marupesan to, moratecanto
Kimi koyna shi moruho
Kimi koyna shi moruho hafua
新たせに 破滅歌
A new song of destruction
獣となり時
Becoming a beast in time
奪い去る針の調べ
The stolen melody of needles
輪廻の火と民
The fire of reincarnation and the people
死とはばたく網
Death flutters in the net
恋暗い白から
Love from the dark white
いつドア遠く聞こえ
When will the door sound far away
甘い記録羽騒ぐ
Sweet memories whispering
黒い花あの声が
The black flower, that voice
壊れた目のあるまま
With broken eyes as they are
黒い花あの歌が
The black flower, that song
作り間いつあるまま
Being created as it is
新たせに 氷歌
A new ice song
悪夢な舞う日を
Dancing on nightmare days
無と断ち切るしゃう
Cutting off nothingness
行く赤い森から
From the red forest to go
忌むへく汚穢はらむ
Cleansing the abhorred filth
弱いあの想い剥がれる
Peeling off those weak thoughts
黒い花あの声が
The black flower, that voice
祈りの違いのあるまま
With differences in prayers
黒い花あの歌が
The black flower, that song
アタラセ リ ハメツアウ タ
Thus the truth sets free amidst the grief and pleas
ケモノト ナリ トキリ
Flowered monsters, lost in the debris
ウバイサ ル ハリノシラベ
Displaced from all time
リンネノ ヒト タリ
The piercing ring of bells
シト ハバタツ アミ
Reborn to a cold hearted world
コイ クライシロカラ
These wings carry my will to end in dusk
イツ オア トオク キコエ
Devotion gently unfolds
アマイ キロクバネ ササメガク
Those from the past whisper from distant dreams
クロイハナ アノコエガ
They hold dear a precious longing for a new time
コワレタメノ アル ママ
Flower, blackest blight
クロイハナ アノウタガツク ライマイツ アル ママ
Sings of tarnished white
イミアタラセ リ コオリアウ タ
Within blindness, blooming, undue new life
アクモナ マウ ヒモト タチキルシカイ
Flower, blackest blight
アカイモリ カライム ベクケガレ
In the dark of night
アラム ヨワイ アノ ホモイ
Forlorn songs of angels, cry of the end of time
ハガレル
Thus the truth sets free that cold song
クロイハナ アノコエガ イノリノチガ アル モモ
That shall be dancing in a woeful nightmare
クロイハナ アノウタガ
Having nothing to weigh my worth
クロイハナ アノウタガ アノ ウタガ
I run from crimson forests
ザンゲノヒガ アル ママ
Calling this flower which bore dark blood
キエエ
Shall ne’er sing of the past
サイヤクワ
As I will forget these somber memories
マチオリル
Flower, blackest blight
コワレタキ
Sings a song of plight
ヒト
Bitter are those prayers now drenched in blood
ユメエ
Flower, blackest blight
クリガエル
Is the song of might
オカレユキ
That will sound a day in which all shall disappear
ユルサレサル
Ruin befalls here
オト ハナシウ チウ
Song of the black flower, let me be free at last
秘密の黄昏に
I held your hand
君の手を取った
During the secret sunset
古のバラード
Yarning, like repeating
繰り返すように紡ぐ
The ancient ballad
Romance of life
君のことをいつも歌いたい
I always want to sing of you
悲しい夜を温もりで満たして
Filling the sad nights with warmth
愛を見つけて
I find love
ヒナギクが咲いていた
Daisies were blooming
白い月輝いていた
The white moon was shining
君の咳で始まるよ
It starts with your whispering
永久のstoria
Eternity's storia
秘密の黄昏に
In the secret twilight
君の手を採った
I took your hand
古のバラード
An ancient ballad
繰り返すように紡ぐ
Spinning as if repeating
romance of life
君のことをいつも歌いたい
I want to sing of you always
悲しい夜を温もりで満たして
Fill the sad night with warmth
愛を見つけて
Find love
雛菊が咲いていて
Hina daisies were blooming
白い月輝いていた
The white moon was shining
君の呟きで始まるよ
It begins with your whisper
永遠のstoria
Eternal storia
水の中沈んでいた
Sank into the water
懐かしい恋の物語
A nostalgic love story
光と影の中から
From within light and shadow
愛しさは生まれて
Love is born
還る
Returning
君の目を見ていた
I was looking into your eyes
その腕の中で
In those arms
恋人の呟き
A lover's whisper
星屑のチーター
Stardust zither
古のバラード
An ancient ballad
泉を満たして
Fill the spring
風は西へ
The wind is to the west
優しい歌を君と歌いたい
I want to sing a gentle song with you
五月の月が今此処にある
The May moon is here now
恋の歌が今宵響くから
Because a love song echoes tonight
冷たい胸を温もりで満たして
Fill the cold chest with warmth
語ろう
Let's talk
愛のstoria
Love's storia
あれ？大丈夫？
Huh? Are you okay?
大丈夫？
Are you okay?
ですかる？
Are you?
あれ、動ける！動ける！
Oh, we can move!
動ける！やったーやったー！
We can move! We did it!
動けるってなるとね、テンション上がるね。
We can move again!
やったー！
We did it!
いつものやつだ。
It's always like this.
えー！
Yeah!
また動けるようになったぞ！
We can move again!
よかった。一人……誰が？
Wait, did someone save us?
いなちゃんか？
Was it Ina-chan?
助けてくれたやつ。
Who saved us?
なんとか、なんとか
Somehow...
ビョンってしたら、
You posed like this...
あ、動けるようになった！嬉しい、よかった！
Oh, we can move again! I'm so happy!
なんで一緒に、なっ、てたんですか？
Why did we end up like that?
なんでだっけ？
Why was it again?
なんかね、
Something...
なんか見たよね。
We saw something, right?
なんかね。
Something...
なんかいた。なんかいたんだよね。
Someone was there.
翼さが……
Wings...
翼が？
Wings?
リュウっぽかったかな？リュウ？
Was it a dragon?
リュウっぽかったかな？リュウっぽかった。
A dragon? It might have been a dragon.
気はするけど、なんかっ、違うかっ、と、思った！
It felt like it, but...
忘れた！忘れた！
Wait, I forgot!
ごめん、ごめん！もう忘れてないけど。
Sorry, sorry! I forgot.
あ、そういえば、そういえば
Oh, by the way...
いなちゃん、はい！あなた誕生日！
Ina-chan, it's your birthday!
そうです、誕生日です！
That's right, it's your birthday!
おめでとうございます！
Happy birthday!
いやあ、大好きな二人と一緒って嬉しい！
Yeah, I'm so happy to be with my two favorite people!
嬉しい！嬉しい！
So happy!
なんか、いなちゃんとね、同期生はね、ま、言うたらデビュー日近かったもんね。
Also, Ina-chan and us...
そうですね。1ヶ月……そう、1ヶ月ぐらいだったから、なんかもう同期、同期みたいな。
Yeah, about a month apart.
同期みたいな。同期！うん。
It's like we're classmates!
同期みたいな感じだから。
It feels like we're classmates!
嬉しい。
That's amazing!
そうですね、でもシロとね、中々歌う機会が少ないなっていう今回。
That's true, but Shirotan and I don't get many chances to sing together.
うん、今回なんか、いや、いつか、いつか、なんかお互い先輩としてシロちゃんと歌いたいだって。
So this time, I was like, "Someday I want to sing with Shirotan!"
セットでいいんですか？うれしいね！ね、うれしい！ね、ふたり、ふたり、うれしい！
We finally did it!
ふたりの歌声めっちゃ聴きたいたいたい大好きなので、うれしい！
I wanted to sing together so much because I love you both!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
みんなも、だいだいだいだいすきだよ！
We love you so, so, so much!
うれしい！
Yay!
いや、私の方が好きだから！
Well, I love you more!
いやいや、私の方が好きだから！私の方が好きだから！
No, no, I love you more!
いや、私の方が好きだから！やめて、やめて！
No, I love you more!
どっちが好きなの？
Which one of us do you love more?
なんかみんなの衣装さ
Somehow everyone's outfits...
あれ、みんなさ、なんか服が可愛くなってる、とかさ？
Hey, aren't everyone's clothes looking super cute?
すっごい、なんか
They're so, like—
なんか、ドアがあって、ドアをぴょんとしたらこの衣装になりますみたいな。
Like, there's a door, and if you hop through it, you get this outfit.
え、やば！似合ってる！可愛い！
Whoa, no way! It suits you! So cute!
よく見たらさ、タコ足…
If you look closely, octopus legs...
タコ足いっぱいだよ、これ！
There are so many octopus legs on this!
いっぱいあるんだよな、これ。靴も！靴も！
There's so many, right here. Even the shoes!
タコ足ね！
Octopus legs!
靴もタコ足ね！
The shoes are octopus legs too!
あ、そう、タコ足なの！
Ah, right, they're octopus legs!
可愛くない？
Aren't they cute?
おしゃれだね。
So stylish.
ねえ、いいの？
Hey, is this okay?
いや、でも、嬉しい、この……ううう、嬉しい！うわ、ちょっとよくわかんない、嬉しい！嬉しい！
Yeah, but I'm so happy, this... uuu, I'm so happy! Woah, I don't even know what to say, I'm so happy!
こちらこそだよ。
Same here.
あ、でも、え、あなたちょっと時間があるじゃないのよ。
Ah, but hey, you actually have some time right now, don't you?
え、もう時間？
Eh, time already?
あ、やばい、やばい！
Ah, oh no, oh no!
は、もう行かなきゃかも。
Ha, I might have to go already.
終わらないの収録を、あなたあるじゃないのよ！やばい、やばい！
You have that unfinished recording session to do! Oh no, oh no!
飛行機乗らなきゃ！ちょっと飛行機乗って行かないといけないから
I gotta catch a plane! I gotta hop on a plane and go!
あ、またね！ありがとうね！
Ah, see you later! Thanks so much!
バイバイ！バイバイ！バイバイ！
Bye-bye! Bye-bye! Bye-bye!
なんか、なんかおるぞ。
Wait, someone's over there.
なんだあれ？なんだこれ？なんだあれ？
What is that? What is this? What is that?
気になるな。
I'm curious.
急げ急げ！
Hurry, hurry!
あ、急がなきゃ。
Ah, I gotta hurry.
That was so fun!
I got to finally sing Leslie Dillon, and of course with Watame-senpai.
I'm so, so happy, you know.
They did say they saw something like a dragon, a dragon.
But you know, after all this singing and dancing, I'm kind of, kind of getting sleepy, so I'm just just gonna take a, you know, small nap, okay? I'm gonna take a small nap, so...
But you know, after all this singing and dancing, I'm kind of getting sleepy, so I'm just gonna take a small nap, okay?
Okay.
Yeah. I'll just go, go.
draco in fabula
in dracone hora
in dracone spes
in dracone error
in dracone veritas
in dracone somnium
in dracone fatum
in dracone causa
in dracone amor
音のない大地に 恋の歌 響けば
As a love song rings out across a silent land,
狂い出す歯車 止められぬ宿命が はじけた
gears spin out of control, and fate springs into motion.
蘇る今 にしえより
Now it revives from the ancient past,
寂寥の恋 目覚めた
awakening a desolate love.
絆を求めて 炎はほとばしる
Seeking a connection, flames jet forth.
破壊と再生 気高き君の呪縛
Exalted one, bound by the curse of rebirth and destruction.
draco in fabula
in dracone hora
in dracone spes
in dracone error
in dracone veritas
in dracone somnium
in dracone fatum
in dracone causa
in dracone amor
透き通る魂 嘘もなく 気高く
Hers was a pure, noble, and unsullied soul.
原罪を抱えて 未熟な恋 求む愚かさ
How foolish of her to embrace sin and seek immature love.
月明かり今 ふたり 照らす
Now the moonlight illuminates the two,
東の間の時 重ねた
sharing a fleeting moment together.
絆の行方を 両手で抱きしめた
You embraced that connection in your arms.
終わりと始まり 貴き君の記憶
Noble one, your memory holds the beginning and the end.
draco in fabula
in dracone hora
in dracone spes
in dracone error
in dracone veritas
in dracone somnium
in dracone fatum
in dracone causa
in dracone amor
絆を求めて 炎はほとばしる
Seeking a connection, flames jet forth.
破壊と再生 気高き君の呪縛
Exalted one, bound by the curse of rebirth and destruction.
絆の行方を 両手で抱きしめた
You embraced that connection in your arms.
終わりと始まり 貴き君の記憶
Noble one, your memory holds the beginning and the end.
draco in fabula
in dracone hora
in dracone spes
in dracone error
in dracone veritas
in dracone somnium
in dracone fatum
in dracone causa
in dracone amor
draco in fabula
The dragon of legend
in dracone hora in dracone spes
In dragons, time; in dragons, hope
in dracone error in dracone veritas
In dragons, uncertainty; in dragons, truth
in dracone somnium in dracone fatum
In dragons, dreams; in dragons, fate
in dracone causa in dracone amor
In dragons, reason; in dragons, love
音のない大地に恋の歌響けば
As a love song rings out across a silent land,
狂い出す歯車 止められぬ宿命がはじまった
gears spin out of control, and fate begins.
蘇る今 いにしえより
Now it revives from the ancient past,
寂寥の恋 目覚めた
awakening a desolate love.
絆を求めて 炎はほとばしる
Seeking a connection, flames jet forth;
破壊と再生 気高き君の呪縛
exalted one, cursed to repeat rebirth.
draco in fabula
The dragon of legend
in dracone hora in dracone spes
In dragons, time; in dragons, hope
in dracone error in dracone veritas
In dragons, uncertainty; in dragons, truth
in dracone somnium in dracone fatum
In dragons, dreams; in dragons, fate
in dracone causa in dracone amor
In dragons, reason; in dragons, love
透き通る魂 嘘もなく気高く
Hers was a pure soul, noble and unsullied,
原罪を抱えて 未熟な恋求める愚かさ
embracing sin in her search for immature love.
月明かり今 ふたり照らす
Now the moonlight illuminates the two
束の間の時 重ねた
as they spend a fleeting moment together.
絆の行方を両手で抱きしめた
You held that connection in your arms;
終わりと始まり 貴き君の記憶
noble one, your memory holds the end.
Shol parn moi him
Ar charuk noishin
Da kalek taifur
Maleik fuidir aslar thern spòr
Yu tantera hodre kanorek
Fu lonly aboyo migendaya krocken hoei kainerakalar
Fu lonly aboyo migendaya krocken hoei yumo teigor milen tala bai roju
Shol parn moi him
Ar charuk noishin
Da kalek taifur
Maleik fuidir aslar thern spòr
Yu tantera hodre kanorek
Fu lonly aboyo migendaya krocken hoei kainerakanar
Fu lonly aboyo migendaya krocken hoei yumo teigor milen tala bai roju
時の揺りかごで
Within the cradle of time,
冷たい夢を見る
seeing a cold dream.
君が歌ってくれた
You sang for me
優しい 優しい 子守唄
a gentle, gentle lullaby.
君が望んだのは
What did you wish for?
終わらぬ世界
— A world that doesn't end —
俺が望むのは
What I wished for
世界の終わり…?
— The end of the world…? —
選ばれし声は
The chosen voice
迷い、憂い、
is confused and sorrowful,
［笑い、労い］
— smiling, comforting —
歌う
singing
悲しみを
turning grief
喜びに見立てて
into joy.
凍りついて 抜け出せずに
Frozen, unable to escape,
君は朽ちていくの?
are you decaying?
ともに耐え抜こうこの世界
Let's endure this world together
ただ君だけを求めて交わらない
seeking only you, never intersecting.
巡り巡る命は この手で
Circling life, with these hands
安らぎと祝福を
giving peace and blessings
終わらせたい 届かない
wanting to end it, unable to reach
孤独の願いは 虚しさを残して
the wish of solitude leaves emptiness behind.
始まる ［全てを照らして］
Beginning — shining on everything —
痛みを、苦しみを 背負わされても
Even when burdened with pain and suffering,
逃れられない運命を 全て今、解き放つ
release all inescapable fate right now.
君が望んだのは ［あなたの未来］
What you wished for — your future —
俺が望んだのは ［戻らぬあの日…］
What I wished for — that day which cannot return —
追い続けたのは 優しい笑顔
What I kept chasing was a gentle smile,
それだけなのに 終わらない
even though that's all, it doesn't end.
続くほど 歌声を
The more it continues, the singing voice
悲鳴に変えて 叫び続ける
turning into screams, continuing to scream.
終わらせたいさだめなら せめて今の
If it's a fate you want to end, at least now
祈りの 果てしく 遠く遠く
far, far to the end of prayer.
歌よ 響け 巡り巡る世界に
Let the song resound through the circling world,
安らぎと祝福を 光を、運命を、
give peace and blessings, light, fate,
闇を、解き放て 終わらない絶望を
release darkness, turn endless despair
歌声に、希望に変えて 叫び続けて
into hope with your singing voice, continuing to scream.
ただ祈る せめて今の 祈りの
Only praying, at least now, of prayer
果てしく 遠く遠く 歌よ 響いて
far, far to the end, let the song resound.
君が望んだのは 俺が望んだのは
What you wished for, what I wished for
残された声は 嘆き
The voice left behind is a sigh,
君を想いながら 独り、君のために歌う
thinking of you, alone, I sing for your sake.
独り、君のために歌う 命を この手で
Alone, I sing for your sake, putting life with these hands
全て、眠らせたら 巡り巡る世界に
to sleep entirely in the circling world,
安らぎと祝福を ああ、朽ちていく
peace and blessings, ah, decaying
運命は終わり この身は君となら
fate ends, this body if with you
どこまででも 始まる声 全て叶えて
wherever it goes, the starting voice fulfilling everything,
未来を照らして 滅び、散らゆく
shining on the future, perishing and scattering
この身とともに 永遠に続くレクイエム
along with this body, an endless requiem.
抗えない運命を 光を、運命を、
Inescapable fate, light, fate,
全て今、解き放ち 闇を解き放ち
release everything now, release darkness
光の底に、眠れ
sleep at the bottom of the light.
Are you okay?
Oh my god, finally you've come!
Seriously, I waited like a hundred years, man! What took you so long?
Hundred years?
How, Google, how long does a rat live?
Man, my muscles are so rigid from being stuck as a statue, but thank you so much for saving...
You know what? In anime, the hero is here to save you.
Oh, thank you.
Yeah, with the beard! The evil dragon!
That's right!
I don't know if you saw, but there was an evil dragon.
Sub's right! Yeah!
That's right! Yeah!
How dare you!
Are you, are you okay? Are you all good? All good?
Are you—are you okay? Are you all good? All good?
Yeah. Now that you're all well, you might as well say a thing.
Yeah. Now that you're all well, you might as well say the thing.
Say, say the thing. You know, the thing, the thing, what thing?
Say—say the thing. You know, the thing! The thing!
You know, like today is a special day.
Oh! Yeah, today is, um... Today is the day that the princess has been saved. Thank you very much! Thank you!
Hugs you, hugs you! Ah, azamas! Azamas! No, no, no, azamas! Ah, azamas!
Hugs you, hugs you! Ah, thanks a lot! Thanks a lot! No, no, no, thanks a lot!
Ba, ba, ba, ba!
Wait, wait, wait, wait!
Do you know what day it is when this spool one become to be?
Do you know what day it is when this spool one becomes to be?
Ah, I see! You're looking for that one.
Yeah, yeah. Okay, okay, okay.
Inato, happy birthday!
Yeah! Thank you for joining me today, Bae!
You're still inviting me. It was so fun. It was so fun. Oh, yeah, it was so fun.
The dance, the dear, the singing with you, it's the best! It's the best!
Yes! I just wanted to say, I know your new outfit is so cute.
Thank you! You like it? It's so cute! Oh, my god!
It's, it's called, what's the outfit called? Yusha!
It's, it's called—what's the outfit called? Yuusha!
Yuusha! Oh, that's right, it looks like a hero, right?
You do look like a hero.
Mhm. My hero! Ooh!
Ah, Bae, and Mr. Squeaks, thanks for leading me to bed!
Thanks, man, you did great. High five! High five! Oh! Man, oh, wasn't for him, I'd be stuck at the statue forever.
Thanks, man, you did great! High five! High five! Oh! Man, oh, if it wasn't for him, I'd be stuck at the statue forever.
Don't shake your head too much, it's gonna fly off.
He needs to do it. It is. Oh, no! There we go, okay, it's all good.
He needs to do it. It is—oh, no! There we go, okay, it's all good.
But, yeah, thank you, Bae, for the journey, you were so fun!
Well, I think, are you still going on a journey? You're continuing your journey after this?
I am a hero! After all, I gotta go see all the princesses that I gotta keep safe.
Excuse me! Huh? It wasn't just me?
All right, let's go! Ah, ha, ha!
Well, that's that. On to the next princess! Let's go!
Many days since then, in fairy tales
Seems trivialized at the end, proof we have seen
I cut a glance from a journey so long
I caught a glimpse from a journey so long,
It was a short journey with you
The ghost can be praised by on this field, shadows of many bested animals
The ghost can be praised upon this field, shadows of many bested animals.
There was a hero who took all foes, a little journey memory with you
No more pages left in that story, our hero goes into slumbering
Leaving behind a veil of peaceful all, saving the doors of a before
leaving behind a veil of peace for all, saving the doors of a before.
The flow time erases it without mercy, and arrows all memories and use
The flow of time erases it without mercy, and arrows all memories and use,
Even the tree she's left in life for now, rustling his diamonds use and yet
I keep all your hope, all the words and wishes courageous one
I keep all your hopes, all the words and wishes, courageous one.
So dwell inside me and even now in my heart
Keep moving through
And all the series shared the same path, and nothing more to thought so it should have been
But suddenly I was wondering, all those tears so Linda my cheeks, why did they come out and fall?
but suddenly I was wondering, all those tears so lonesome cheeks, why did they come out and fall?
I want to find out, until even right now, if I engage in, the journey we met out again
Though I am no longer walking next to you, one day I know I'll find the truth
Ending in fast the new story, also not people for in this journey story
I'm not tasteless go on forever, ever, ever, ever seen that one
Another story Unfolds into a journey
that alone I set out to, I need the locals of every town I stop in, they are our recalling
The person that you were, and neighbor and kindness is spoken of you, acting all cool in
the person that you were, unneighbor and kindness is spoken of you, acting all cool in
everything you do, here and there we can find scatters and balls around, many things that always will prove these
And even that, what's a thermis so one day, I wouldn't find myself alone becoming lonely
And I call to mind every moment of our journey
Many days since then, in fairy tales, seems trivialized at the end proof we have seen
It was that moment our free fully, thank you percent of the journey style of me
Even if your courage is swept, away to the bestness, and all when I seek him what everybody can recall
I will bring you on with me into the future spine
taking your head and, and though it'll begin right at that time, when day and everyday shines, the moment ignited in love
serve with you remain by reflections, all those times go on as brightly shining scenes
Many days tinted in fairy tale scenes,
have arrived at the end, proof we have seen,
long-overdue trip from which I cut out a passage,
evermore gently telling bright at me without a sound,
I'm perceiving you around.
And the hero forever, ever, ever, ask for how long
Now a new beginning has begun to be,
and in this land that you protected and kept in safety,
Yay, and then they lived happily ever after...
or should I say, evermore!
Well yeah, thank you guys for watching today!
I hope you guys enjoyed it. Make sure you, you know,
tell me how it was using the hashtag.
And of course, since it is my birthday, I also have to introduce some of my birthday merch to you guys! Yay!
So we have these items for... the birthday merch this year, let's see. Tada!
Okay, with the first item we have the reversible tote bag!
It has a different design on each side, so depending on what you feel like having on the outside,
you can choose between the lovely key visual by chibi sensei, or a very simplified design to be more incognito!
And of course, we have another one. So, next!
We have the Takodame! Shaker acrylic keychain!
This one, I designed myself, and we wanted it kind of like, you know, you can carry it around and it kind of seems like a little game
that you can play and you can shake it around and the Takodachis will shake. It's a really fun item.
And then, next we also have...
the Takodachi cable tie (set of 2) where you can organize the messy messy chaos that is the cables in your bag, like, like me.
But yeah, I hope they're useful. And last but not least, we have the... next...
Yusha Ina! Aka, Ninomae Ina'nis the hero. This outfit, I call myself the hero.
It's like little cute plushie keychain that you can carry around everywhere and I will protect you. It's a lucky charm! But yeah.
And of course, there is a full set bonus which is going to be a limited... or or we'll have a limited edition postcard.
But if you buy the set, you also get the postcard. There's a limited set and a not limited set. So, there's that.
And of course, we also have a special hololive TCG card with the key art! It's like a thank you bonus for the complete set of the merch.
You know, this card will only be given to customers who purchase the hololive production... oh, purchased from the hololive production official shop.
And this is a Oshi holomem card which you can use only one in the game. I know there's a whole bunch of rules that you can check out on the website.
Unfortunately, it's only the Japanese version, there's only Japanese text on it, but you know, it's kind of like a special limited thing. So, something nice to have.
But yeah, that is it for merch announcement etc. I hope you guys enjoyed the live today!
And of course, we still have the omake, the little ending kind of snippets in the end and the credits. So please look forward to that.
Until next time! Thank you again everyone! Have a wonderful rest of the morning, afternoon, or evening! I'll see you guys later. Bye-bye!
Thanks for watching everyone!!
I'm really happy that I was able to share this special day with you today!
Did you enjoy the live? Do you like the new outfit?! hehe
Just like the theme of the outfit, I would like to continue to do my bestest with everything I do!
... because that is what a hero... yuusha would do!
...because that is what a hero... yuusha would do!
Thank you for cheering for me! always!! I really wouldn't be here without all your support!
and of course, BIG thank you to all the staff & creators that could make this happen too!!
I am always indebted to everyone's passion!
THANK YOU THANK YOU & THANK YOU!
It's time... TO GO NEXT!!